JACK CHEN

REACT DEVELOPER AND ASPIRING GAME DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

СО	NTACT	
	0421223629	

jack.x.chen@outlook.com

jakxc-portfolio.netlify.app

Brisbane, QLD

HOBBIES

- Game Design/Development
- Graphic Design (in particular designing sprites for games)
- Reading, particularly Manga (Song of the Night Walker is a personal favourite)
- Bicycle Riding
- PC Gaming (MMORPGs and MOBAs)

SKILLS

- Fast Learner
- Adaptability
- Hard Working
- Collaboration & Teamwork
- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- React JS
- QT/QML
- Adobe Illustrator
- Git/Version Control
- Game Development (Unity)
- C#

REFERENCES

References available upon request.

PROFILE

I have studied and work in the field of UX/UI design and development, working as a Front End Developer and a User Experience Engineer. I have experience and am familiar with many front end tech stacks such as QT/QML, HTML/CSS, React, JSX and TypeScript. I also have experience using Adobe Indesign, Adobe Illustration and Blender (3D modelling). I am always eager and willing to adapt and learn new tech stacks. Creating visually aesthetic front end, full stack applications and games (Unity Game Engine mainly) is something I not only enjoy to do as a career but as a pastime as well.

.....

WORK EXPERIENCE

User Experience Engineer

YOueue

Jan 2020 - Jul 2022

- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- UI development of multiple applications using QT/QML
- Involved in Software QA (Quality Assurance) for POS application
- Assigned as Lead UI Developer for a version of Kiosk application.

Front End Developer

My Practical Support

Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Designed and implemented their company website using HTML/CSS and Javascript as well as leading design for the online store and magazine
- Worked with Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign and Adobe Photoshop to create templates, icons etc for the company.

React Developer

Bicycle Queensland

Mar 2019 - Nov 2019

- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Proposed and developed a phone application for Bicycle Queensland that offers information and tracking on UV exposure, specifically for cyclists .
- Wireframing to building/development of the app using React JS. Specific role in development of the application include gathering weather data from an API and displaying data on screen using various React hook

JACK CHEN

REACT DEVELOPER AND ASPIRING GAME DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology, Majoring in User Experience Design

University of Queensland

Feb 2016 - Dec 2019

- Awarded Best Non-Thesis Project for University of Queensland 2019 ITEE Innovation Showcase.
- Participated in GovHack Brisbane 2019.
- Invited to present DECO3850 Project on University of Queensland Open Day 2019.

Complete C# Unity Game Developer 2D: Game Development

Udemy

July 2022 - Aug 2022

- Solid foundation for game design and game development through Unity
- Used object oriented programming works in practice.
- Created five 2D Unity Games for Web, Mac & PC.
- Transferable skills developed from this course that can used in .NET, other languages, and more.

Unity RPG Core Combat Creator: Learn Intermediate C# Coding

Gamedev.tv

July 2022 - Aug 2022

- Created core combat mechanics for melee, ranged and special attacks.
- Created pathfinding systems and patrol paths for enemies and NPCs.
- Balance the player and enemy stats (eg. health, damage, movement, attack speed, and more).
- Used C# techniques such as interfaces, delegates, and co-routines.
- Make a detailed level with terrain, enemies, triggers, lighting, particles and other assets.
- Advanced game design, project management and code architecture strategies.

Unity RPG Inventory Systems: Intermediate C# Game Coding Course

Gamedev.tv

Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

- Implement and lay out of inventory UI (user interface) through Unity UI system
- · Created drag-and-drop system so that players can pick up inventory items and move them to other slots, or drop them into the world.
- Use and modify a tooltip system that gives the player information about their inventory items.